The time will come
这样的时刻将会来临
when,with elation
你得意洋洋地
you will greet yourself arriving at your own door,
站在自家门口
in your own mirror
照着镜子迎接自我的到来
and each will smile at the other's welcome,
以欢笑迎接彼此
and say, sit here. Eat.
并说道，坐这儿。吃吧
You will love again the stranger who was your self.
你将会再次爱上这个陌生人————从前的自己
Give wine.Give bread.Give back your heart to itself,
斟满美酒。递上面包。把心交还其身
to the stranger who has loved you all your life,
给那一辈子爱着你的陌生人
whom you ignored for another,
你曾因为他人而忽略了他
who knows you by heart
他却打心底里懂你
Take down the love letters from the bookshelf,
从书架上取下那些情书
the protographs, the desperate notes,
照片以及绝望的字条
peel your own image from the mirror.
从镜中剥去自己的形象。
Sit. Feast on your life.
坐下。尽享你的生活